All right, if you have not seen this video yet, or you're in for a real treat, eh?
You're about to witness a master class in not letting these pretentious, ignorant, arrogant white people ramp with you and your people.
Why should somebody who maybe had an ancestor seven or eight generations ago, long before they were a twinkle in their great-great-great-great-grandparents' eye,
why should they have to pay now for what an ancient ancestor did, or why should they apologise for what an ancestor did centuries ago?
Why do they still carry that burden?
Oh, it's not a burden at all.
You are one of the beneficiaries of that slave trade, so this is not a burden.
You should be concerned, and you should pay because you today are still benefiting from the greatest indignity to a human being, and that is the slave trade.
And not only did you benefit during the slave trade and your country developed, but look at what it caused the developing world.
During slavery, resources was used to build your country, build up your capacity.
You were able to then become competitive, you were able to invest in mechanisation, and developing countries like ours were left behind.
So you should be very concerned because you are a prime beneficiary of the exploits of slavery.
So put a figure on it, please, because it always comes down to the bottom line.
How much should an individual taxpayer in a country like the UK be signing a cheque to a country like yours?
Well, it's easy to calculate. We can use the time value of money.
You can look at the period of slavery and the contribution that, well, not the contribution, the extraction of wealth from countries like ours.
It is not only the value, it is the loss of time.
I just wonder, people will be wondering, I mean, are we talking billions, millions? What would you expect?
The calculation goes into billions for the region.
And this is the problem. We live in a very unjust society.
You know, we condemn completely the war in Ukraine.
But if you look at the mobilisation of resources in the war in Ukraine, in two years, you have mobilised more support for Ukraine than we have mobilised for Haiti for 60 years.
You have mobilised more support for Ukraine than we have mobilised for Palestine for 20 years.
You have mobilised more support for Ukraine in just one and a half years than we mobilised to address the issue of hunger in Africa for three years.
And that is the type of, you know, unjust way we have been dealing with these crises.
And we are not going to tolerate the injustice that occurred during slavery to be compared with any other system.
Slavery, we all agree, was the greatest injustice ever done to human beings.
So we should not ever try to compare this to any other system.
There is no other system that has created greater injustice than slavery and indignity to humankind and slavery.
One of the points you're going to be making today is about our royal family.
And you feel that it's not just about the finances involved here in terms of reparations for slavery.
It's about the gestures.
And you think that the British royal family should make a big gesture, don't you?
What do you mean? Hand over a palace to your country?
We don't want the British to hand over a palace that we built.
So if you go into many of the palaces in Britain, you will see the lovely green heartwood from Guyana.
You will see the sweat, tears and blood of the slaves who were exploited.
So what do you want?
And the revenue that was earned from their exploitation.
So we are not asking for a palace.
We are asking for justice and a fair form of justice to the ancestors
and to the greatest injustice that has ever been done to human beings.
We look...
Moraskont.